<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>monetary-policy on Nasser&#39;s personal website</title>
    <link>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/tags/monetary-policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in monetary-policy on Nasser&#39;s personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nasseralkmim.github.io/tags/monetary-policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Does monetary easing causes &#34;asset inflation&#34;?</title>
      <link>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/asset-price-inflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/asset-price-inflation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   Some people say that monetary easing by the central bank in the past decade is not affecting the CPI but the asset prices (stocks and bonds).
 To see how this is wrong (?) we need to understand inflation, monetary policy and modern finance.
  Inflation   Results from excess demand for goods and the ability of the supply side to provide.
Monetarist   Right wingers can be so fanciful about their intellectual inheritance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow banking and FED as a lender of last resort</title>
      <link>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/shadow-banking-monetary-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/shadow-banking-monetary-policy/</guid>
      <description>Traditional crisis   During a traditional crises, with mostly traditional banks1, the cash commitments are greater than the cash flows. So, there is a liquidity problem for the banks. The FED can directly provide that liquidity by increasing banks reserves.
  References    https://voxeu.org/article/growth-non-bank-finance-and-new-monetary-policy-tools     Footnotes   1 Traditional banks accept deposits (short term borrowing) and make loas (long term lending).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monetary policy and lender of last resort</title>
      <link>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/fed-monetary-mechanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 20:08:58 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/fed-monetary-mechanism/</guid>
      <description>Traditional MP  FED  FED uses its reserves (liabilities) to affect the Federal Funds Rate (FFR), short term interest rate.
 If the FED reduces reserves, buying T-Bills in the open market operations, it affects the FFR upwards.
  Money Market dealers  Money market (MM) dealers are directly affected because they borrow short (overnight) and lend in term (3 months).
 If the financing cost increases, the MM dealers also push the term price upwards.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
