<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>emacs on Nasser&#39;s personal website</title>
    <link>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emacs on Nasser&#39;s personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nasseralkmim.github.io/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Development environment in Emacs</title>
      <link>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/cpp-environment-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/cpp-environment-setup/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   This set up already starts with wsl (version 2) already installed and emacs as well. Emacs on windows with WSL2 | Nasser&amp;#39;s personal website
 This guide also is helpful to set up emacs for c++ development: Configuring Emacs as a C/C++ IDE - LSP Mode - LSP support for Emacs.
  Emacs  Lsp-mode clangd server   clangd is language server that provides intelligent features to emacs (client) via lsp-mode (client-server application).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD setup</title>
      <link>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/phd-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/phd-setup/</guid>
      <description>Emacs  Emacs, of course.
 Tried briefly overleaf, it was good first. Nice to have instant previews and so on.
 But then, it got little complicated with the bibliography export from Zotero. If I add a reference to zotero I have to manually update the bibliography, and it also takes some time to update. Real downside.
 Another minor problem that I anticipated is when I create figures with scripts, I would have to manually upload then (?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs on windows with WSL2</title>
      <link>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/emacs-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/emacs-windows/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   Build emacs inside windows subsystem for linux (wsl). The main advantage is that emacs is considerably faster when using LSP.
  Reference for installation   GitHub - hubisan/emacs-wsl: Install and run emacs with the Windows Subsystem …
  Shortcut   One .bat file that starts the vcxsrv is it nor already running and calls the power shell script that starts emacs. @echo off TASKLIST | FINDSTR vcxsrv || start &amp;#34;&amp;#34; &amp;#34;C:\Program Files\VcXsrv\vcxsrv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I manage academic sources in emacs</title>
      <link>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/bibliography-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nasseralkmim.github.io/notes/bibliography-management/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   In this post I will go over my workflow for managing academic resources and seamless add citation into a $\LaTeX$ file. Usually this process is boring since you have to add a source into your .bib file, then insert the citation with the bibtex key into your latex to generate the references section. This process is independent of your .pdf source, so you can add citation for source that you have physically.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
